guidewire.com 2019-08-24

# Privacy Policy | Guidewire

Effective: May 25, 2018

This Privacy Policy provides information about data we collect, use, and share, and our commitment to using the personal information we collect in a respectful fashion.

  * Scope of this Policy
  * Privacy Shield Framework
  * What personal information do we gather?
  * How do we collect your personal information?
  * How do we use your personal information?
  * Do we share your information with outside parties?
  * What about security?
  * Do we give you access to your information?
  * Using your personal information to contact you
  * How can you unsubscribe from our database?
  * Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies.
  * Behavioral Targeting/ Re-Targeting.
  * Blog.
  * Social Media Widgets.
  * General Data Protection Regulation (“GDPR”)
  * Updating this Privacy Policy.
  * General.

**Scope of this Policy**

This Privacy Policy explains our policies and practices regarding the collection, use, storage, and disclosure of your personal information on our website [www.guidewire.com](http://www.guidewire.com/) owned and operated by Guidewire Software, Inc. (also called “Guidewire,” Guidewire Software,” and “We” in this Privacy Policy). It also describes the choices available to you regarding the use of, your access to, and how to update and correct your personal information. We want you to feel secure when visiting our web site and are committed to maintaining your privacy when doing so. The Guidewire Software site may contain links to other web sites. Guidewire Software is not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such web sites. The information below provides an overview of how we protect your privacy.

**Privacy Shield Framework**

Guidewire Software participates in and has certified its compliance with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and the Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework. Guidewire is committed to subjecting all personal data received from European Union (EU) member countries and Switzerland, respectively, in reliance on each Privacy Shield Framework, to the Framework’s applicable Principles.  To learn more about the Privacy Shield Framework, visit the U.S. Department of Commerce’s [Privacy Shield List](https://www.privacyshield.gov/list).

Guidewire is responsible for the processing of personal data it receives, under the Privacy Shield Framework, and subsequently transfers to a third party acting as an agent on its behalf. Guidewire complies with the Privacy Shield Principles for all onward transfers of personal data from EU and Switzerland, including the onward transfer liability provisions.

With respect to personal data received or transferred pursuant to the Privacy Shield Framework, Guidewire is subject to the regulatory enforcement powers of the U.S. Federal Trade Commission. In certain situations, Guidewire may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.

If you have an unresolved privacy or data use concern that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third party dispute resolution provider (free of charge) at <https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request>.

Under certain conditions, more fully described on the [Privacy Shield website](https://www.privacyshield.gov/article?id=How-to-Submit-a-Complaint), you may invoke binding arbitration when other dispute resolution procedures have been exhausted.

**1\. What personal information do we gather?**  
There are times when we may need information from you, which includes your Internet address so that we can track unique visits to our site for analytic purposes. Additionally, we may need your personal information such as your name, and your postal and email address in order to grant you access to protected and secured sites or provide you with the opportunity to register for an event, to fulfill your requests for information including white papers, download updates to our products, or participate in an online survey. In other instances, we may ask you to provide us with information such as your product interests so that we can send you only the information that is useful to you, including articles, product and service alerts, new product and service announcements and event invitations.

If you wish to apply for a job within the careers section of the site, we will collect personal information about you such as name, email address, and phone number. We will also ask you to provide us with a cover letter and a resume. We use this information to contact you regarding the position in which you expressed interest, to determine whether or not you are qualified for the position and to contact you regarding setting up an interview.

If you choose to let us know on who introduced you to an opportunity found our career page, we will ask you for your referral’s name and email address. We will automatically send your referral a one-time email indicating you have been referred. We may store this information for the sole purpose of sending this one-time email and/or for tracking the success of our referral program. You or your referral may contact us at info [at] guidewire.com to request that we remove this information from our database.

**2\. How do we collect your personal information?**  
We collect information directly through response forms that you choose to complete. We may also collect information indirectly through the use of cookies. The cookies we use identify you only as a number. "Persistent" cookies are stored on your computer and used in subsequent visits to our sites. "Session" cookies only exist for a specific visit. You can disable your computer from accepting one or both cookie types by changing the settings in the preferences or options menu in your browser. If you disable both types, most of the .com site will function, but you will not be able to log in to certain portions of our support site (Downloads or Knowledge Base pages). If you disable "persistent" cookies, but not "session" cookies, these pages should still function. We do not link the information we store in cookies to any personal information you submit while on our site.

**3\. How do we use your personal information?**  
Information we collect is used to determine what is most effective about our web site, to help us identify ways to improve sites, to personalize the visit for you through the use of "persistent cookies" if you permit it, and to determine how we can tailor our web site to make it more effective. We may also use data for other purposes, which we would describe to you at the point we collect the information (for example, if you are invited to register for an event or request more information about one of our products). When you supply Guidewire Software with your personal information, we may use the information to learn more about you so that we can develop better products and services or use the information, sharing it with our business partners, to inform you about new products, services and offers that may be of interest to you.

Information we collect from the careers section of the site will be used to help us determine how suitable you are for employment by Guidewire. We might also use it for statistical analysis – for diversity monitoring, or to assess the success of our advertising campaigns, for example. And any information you submit as part of your application may be verified. This could mean we check your qualifications, or that we'll contact your references. We won't contact your current employer, without your permission. We will seek your consent before using your information for any purpose not listed in this Privacy Policy.

We post customer testimonials/videos on our Web site which may contain personal information. We do obtain the customer’s consent via email prior to posting the testimonial or video to post their name along with it. To request removal of your personal information from our testimonials or videos, contact us at info [at] guidewire.com. In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

**4\. Do we share your information with outside parties?**  
We will share your personal information with third parties only in the ways that are described in this privacy policy. We do not sell your personal information to third parties.  Any information you give to Guidewire Software will be held with the utmost care, and will not be used in ways that you have not consented to. We may provide your personal information to service providers who furnish a way for users to submit job applications, sign up for events, and send emails on our behalf. These companies are authorized to use your personal information only as necessary to provide these services to us.

Guidewire has contracted with a trusted third party provider to manage its online employment application process. Guidewire's third party provider has agreed to comply with all regulations designed to protect your privacy. It will only use candidate information to process Guidewire employment applications and not for its own purposes. It will not disclose any personally identifiable information to any third party. During the recruitment process, candidate information will be accessed internally only by those Guidewire employees who are directly involved in the recruitment process.

In certain situations, Guidewire may be required to disclose personal information in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements. We may also disclose your personal information as required by law, such as to comply with a subpoena, or similar legal process, when we believe in good faith that disclosure is necessary to protect our rights, protect your safety or the safety of others, investigate fraud, or respond to a government request.

If we are involved in a merger, acquisition, or sale of all or a portion of our assets, you will be notified via email and/or prominent notice on our Web site of any change in ownership or uses of your personal information, as well as any choices you may have regarding your personal information.

This Web site contains links to other sites that are not owned or controlled by us. Please be aware that we are not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites.

We encourage you to be aware when you leave our site and to read the privacy policies of each and every Web site that collects personal information.

This privacy policy applies only to information collected by this Web site.

**5\. What about security?**  
The security of your personal information is important to Guidewire Software and we take appropriate steps to maintain security of your personal information. The open nature of the Internet is such that data may flow over networks without security measures and may be accessed and used by people other than those for whom the data is intended. While this is out of our control, we aim to apply appropriate levels of security at all times. We use industry standard technologies and maintain current security standards to ensure that your personal information is protected against unauthorized access, disclosure, inappropriate alteration, or misuse.

We manage our server environment appropriately and our firewall infrastructure is strictly adhered to. We routinely employ current technologies to ensure that the confidentiality and privacy of your information is not compromised.

To safeguard against unauthorized access to your accounts, you are required to "sign on" using a user ID and a password to certain secured areas of the [www.guidewire.com](http://www.guidewire.com/) web site. Both user ID and password are encrypted when sent over the Internet. If you are unable to provide the correct password, you will not be able to access these sections. Despite all of our efforts, the Internet is inherently unsecure and we cannot guarantee that information provided online will be secure at all times. Suffice it to say that the security of your personal information is important to us and we will use all reasonable means to keep it as safe as possible.

**6\. Do we give you access to your information?**  
Upon request Guidewire will provide you with information about whether we hold, or process on behalf of a third party, any of your personal information. To request this information please contact us at info [at] guidewire.com.

You are entitled to have access to your information and require it to be corrected or deleted if it is inaccurate. You can do this by contacting us via info [at] guidewire.com or send us a mail through our mailing address below. We will respond to your access request within 30 days.

We will retain your personal information for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you services. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your information to provide you services contact us at info [at] guidewire.com or through our mailing address below. We will retain and use your personal information to fulfill the purposes outlined in this Privacy Policy or as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements.

By entering your personal information in the Guidewire Careers website you accept that we may retain your information and it may be held by Guidewire or by any third party company that processes it on our behalf. We'll store all the information you submit as part of your application. And, in the course of the recruitment process, we might record further information about you. We collect and process sensitive personal data only so far as is necessary to ensure we comply with legal requirements, for example under the equality of opportunity laws. We will retain your information for a minimum of 6 months from your last update, unless otherwise required by law. If you are hired by Guidewire, the personal information you have submitted will be retained as part of your employment record. If you have any question on our handling of personal information, please contact the recruitment team by email at info [at] guidewire.com.

**7\. Using your personal information to contact you.**  
If you have asked to receive communications or provided contact information to download white papers or access other resources, then we will use your name and the email address you provided only to contact you regarding other communications that may be of interest to you.

**8\. How can you unsubscribe from our database?**  
You may change your subscription status at any time by visiting our subscription status page and entering your registered email address. If you registered under multiple addresses you will need to enter each address you wish to unsubscribe. An email will be sent to the address provided in order to ensure that the unsubscribe request is valid. If you are unable to access our subscription status page, you may send an email to unsubscribe [at] guidewire.com and we will notify you of your subscription status. Please be sure to send your request from the email address you wish to unsubscribe or clearly state in the email body the email address you wish to unsubscribe.

You may also opt-out from receiving newsletter or promotional communications by following the instructions included in each newsletter or communication.

If you supply us with your postal address on-line you may receive periodic mailings from us with information on new products and services or upcoming events. If you do not wish to receive such mailings, please let us know by calling us at 650.357.9100 or send a letter to Guidewire Software, 1001 E. Hillsdale Blvd., Foster City, CA 94404. Please provide us with your exact name and address. We will be sure your name is removed from the list we share with other organizations.

Persons who supply us with their telephone numbers on-line may receive telephone contact from us with information regarding new products and services or upcoming events. If you do not wish to receive such telephone calls, please let us know by calling us at the number above or sending us e-mail at the above address.

**9\. Cookies and Other Tracking Technologies.**  
Guidewire Software and our marketing partners use cookies or similar technologies in analyzing trends, administering the site, tracking users’ movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole. We may receive reports based on the use of these technologies by these companies on an individual as well as aggregated basis.

As is true of most web sites, we gather certain information automatically and store it in log files.  This information may include internet protocol (IP) addresses, browser type, internet service provider (ISP), referring/exit pages, operating system, date/time stamp, and/or click stream data to analyze trends in the aggregate and administer the site. We link this automatically collected data to other information we collect about you.

**10\. Behavioral Targeting/ Re-Targeting.**  
We partner with a third party to either display advertising on our Web site or to manage our advertising on other sites. Our third party partner may use technologies such as cookies to gather information about your activities on this site and other sites in order to provide you advertising based upon your browsing activities and interests.  If you wish to not have this information used for the purpose of serving you interest-based ads, you may opt-out by clicking [here](http://preferences-mgr.truste.com/) (or if located in the European Union click [here](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/)). Please note this does not opt you out of being served ads.  You will continue to receive generic ads.

**11\. Blog.**  
Our Web site offers publicly accessible blogs or community forums. You should be aware that any information you provide in these areas may be read, collected, and used by others who access them. To request removal of your personal information from our blog or community forum, contact us at info [at] guidewire.com. In some cases, we may not be able to remove your personal information, in which case we will let you know if we are unable to do so and why.

**12\. Social Media Widgets.**  
Our Web site includes Social Media Features, such as the Facebook and Twitter buttons and Widgets, such as the Share this button or interactive mini-programs that run on our site. These Features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on our site, and may set a cookie to enable the Feature to function properly. Social Media Features and Widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on our Site. Your interactions with these Features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it.

**13\. General Data Protection Regulation (“GDPR”).**  
Guidewire is committed to complying with the General Data Protection Regulation.  GDPR expands the privacy rights of individuals based in the European Economic Area (“EEA”), and places new obligations on all organizations that handle personal information of these individuals.  This section provides helpful information on your rights as an individual based in the EEA, and how and why we use your personal information.

Your Rights Under GDPR

If you reside in the European Economic Area (“EEA”), you have the right as a data subject to exercise the following rights by contacting us via the email and postal address in Section 14 below:

  * Right of access – you can request access to your personal information and information about how we process it
  * Right to rectification – you can request to have your personal information corrected if it is inaccurate and/or outdated and to have incomplete personal information completed
  * Right to withdraw consent – you can withdraw consent at anytime if you have previously consented to a certain processing of your personal information (e.g., withdrawing consent previously given to send you marketing communications).
  * Right to erasure (also known as the Right to be Forgotten) – you can request to have your personal information erased, where applicable (e.g., if personal information is no longer necessary in relation to the purposes for which it was collected/processed).
  * Right to restriction of processing – you can restrict the processing of your personal information in certain situations (e.g., if the accuracy of your personal information is contested).
  * Right to data portability – you have the right to receive your personal information electronically in a standard format to transmit it to another controller, where applicable (e.g., if processing is based on your consent).
  * Right to object – you have the right to object to processing of your personal information
  * Rights regarding automated individual decision making, including profiling – you have the right to not be subject to a decision based solely on automated individual decision making, including profiling.
  * Right to lodge a complaint – you have the right to lodge a complaint with a data protection supervisory authority if you believe we are mishandling your personal information under the GDPR requirements.

Depending on your interaction with Guidewire, we may act as a Controller or as a Processor of your personal information.  A Controller determines the purposes and means of the processing of personal information while a Processor processes personal information on behalf of the controller.   If we receive your personal information from our customers, please contact our customer directly with your data subject access request.  Since we act as a Processor for our customers, they are better equipped in assisting you with your request.  We will reasonably support our customers in fulfilling your request.

Purpose of Using and Sharing Your Personal Information

Under GDPR, we can use and share your personal information only where we have a proper reason to do so.  These reasons, known as legal basis, include:

  * Contract Performance/Fulfillment - your personal information is processed in order to fulfill a contractual agreement.  For example, we may use your name and email address to setup a Guidewire account after your purchase of our product.
  * Consent – We can process your personal information if you provide us with consent to do so.  For example, we will send you marketing communication after you provide us with your consent. 
  * Legitimate Interests – Using your personal information for legitimate interests help Guidewire to streamline processes, improve products and services, and to provide an enjoyable user experience while protecting your personal information.
  * Legal Obligation – We will disclose your personal information if we are required to do so by law.  This may include sharing your information for law enforcement purposes.
  * Protecting Data Subject and/or Others – We may disclose personal information if such disclosure is in your vital interest or others.

To help you understand how the use of your personal information and legal basis fits together, we’ve put together the below table.

**What do we use your personal information for?** | **What is our legal basis for processing your personal information?** | **If legitimate interest is listed as one of the legal basis, what is Guidewire’s legitimate interest in using your personal information?**  
---|---|---  
  
To contact you to provide information you requested (e.g., submitting a form via our website)

| 

Consent  
Legitimate Interest

| 

To inform you about new products, services and offers that may be of interest to you  
  
To cooperate with law enforcement, investigate fraud, protect Guidewire’s rights, your safety, and safety of others

| 

Legal Obligation  
Protecting Data Subject or Others  
Legitimate Interests

| 

By using your personal information in this manner, we are continually improving and streamlining how we deal with fraud investigations, comply with applicable legal obligation, and respond to legal request.  
  
To engage in website analytics

| 

Legitimate Interests

| 

We may use cookies or similar technologies in analyzing trends, administering the site, tracking users’ movements around the site and to gather demographic information about our user base as a whole.  
  
To send you marketing communications to inform you of the latest news and announcements from Guidewire and provide you with interest based online advertisements.

| 

Consent  
Legitimate Interests

| 

With your consent, we may send you marketing communications and deliver updates about our products that you may be interested in.  We also provide insights for our product teams with respect to developing products for you.  
  
To contact you to undertake customer satisfaction surveys, invite you to provide product reviews or for market research

| 

Legitimate Interests

| 

We take customers’ feedback into consideration in product development and designs to build features that are customer-centric.  
  
To evaluate your candidacy for employment with Guidewire and to improve recruiting efforts

| 

Consent  
Legitimate Interests  
Legal Obligation

| 

We use personal information to determine whether you are a successful candidate for a position at Guidewire and to improve our recruiting efforts to attract the right candidate pool.  
  
To post customer testimonials/videos on our website

| 

Consent  
Legitimate Interests

| 

With our customer consent, we may post testimonials and videos on our website about our products and services.  
  
You have no obligation to provide us with your personal information on our website as a visitor.  Our customers have certain obligations to supply us with personal information to use our services and products (e.g., providing us with email address to receive maintenance schedule for a specific service)

International Transfer of Personal Information Collected

Your personal information may be processed in countries outside of the EEA. Your personal information may be transferred to and stored by us in the United States and in other countries in which we operate. If your personal information is transferred outside the EEA, we will protect your data by ensuring the recipient has adequate levels of protection in place (e.g., executing Standard Contractual Clauses with the recipient).

**14\. Updating this Privacy Policy.**  
We may update this Privacy Policy to reflect changes to our information practices. If we make any material changes we will notify you by email (sent to the e-mail address specified in your account) or by means of a notice on this Site prior to the change becoming effective. We encourage you to periodically review this page for the latest information on our privacy practices.

**15\. General.**  
Put simply, we value your trust in us. So we want to maintain your privacy and work with you to ensure that this web site and the information and services we provide to you are a valuable resource for you. For any more information about this web site or your visit, please contact us at info [at] guidewire.com.

Guidewire Software, Inc.  
Attn: Privacy Team  
1001 E. Hillsdale Blvd., Suite 800  
Foster City, CA 94404
